Spoon 还是 sboon？连读有趣的一点是，它很大程度上取决于
Spoon or sboon? An interesting thing about liaisons is that so much of it has to do
关键要记住的是：声带不喜欢在中途来回切换。
with whether a consonant is voiced or not. The key thing to remember is that the
声带不喜欢在中途切换。如果第一个辅音是
vocal cords don't like switching around at the midpoint. If the first consonant is
有声的，后一个通常也会有声；如果第一个是无声的，第二个
voiced, the next one will be as well. If the first one is unvoiced, the second one
无论怎么发，听起来都会是无声的。例如，先说 spoon。现在说
will sound unvoiced no matter what you do. For example, say the word spoon. Now say
spoon 这个词。听到它们听起来一样了吗？这就是为什么我希望你总是
the word spoon. Hear how they sound the same? This is why I'd like you to always
说英语时，把介词 to 变成 duh，不管前面是什么音。
convert the preposition to, to duh when you're speaking English, no matter what
前一个音。一开始，为了让你习惯这个概念，我们做了一个
comes before it. In the beginning, to get you used to the concept, we made a
但现在你的 schwa 已经到位了，
distinction between tuh and duh, but now that your schwa is in place, use the
除了句子开头以外，其他位置都会听成一个单独的 duh 音。
single duh sound everywhere, except at the very beginning of a sentence. After a
在有声音后必须这样做；在无声音后也可以这样做。
voiced sound, he had to do it. After an unvoiced sound, he got to do it, at the
句首时则是 to be or not to be。若要检测你的连读，请拨打 800
beginning of a sentence, to be or not to be. To have your liaisons tested, call 800
457-4255。
-457-4255.